mautic.org 2017-05-16

# Privacy Policy

Like most website operators, Mautic.org, Mautic.net and Mautic.com hereafter collectively referred to as Mautic, collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. Mautic’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how Mautic’s visitors use its website. From time to time, Mautic may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

Mautic also collects potentially personally-identifying information (PII) like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses. Mautic does not use such information to identify its visitors, however, and does not disclose such information, other than under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information, as described below.

### Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information

Certain visitors to Mautic’s websites choose to interact with Mautic in ways that require Mautic to gather personally-identifying information (PII). The amount and type of information that Mautic gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who use our forums to provide a username and email address. In each case, Mautic collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with Mautic. Mautic does not disclose PII other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply PII, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

### Aggregated Statistics

Mautic may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its websites. For instance, Mautic may reveal how many downloads a particular version got, or say which plugins are most popular based on checks from api.Mautic.org, a web service used by Mautic installations to check for new versions of Mautic and plugins. However, Mautic does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

### Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information

Mautic discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information (PII) only to those of its employees, contractors, and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on Mautic’s behalf or to provide services available at Mautic’s websites, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using Mautic’s websites, including Mautic.org and Mautic.com, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. Mautic will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and PII to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors, and affiliated organizations, as described above, Mautic discloses potentially personally-identifying and PII only when required to do so by law, or when Mautic believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of Mautic, third parties, or the public at large. If you are a registered user of a Mautic website and have supplied your email address, Mautic may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with Mautic and our products. We primarily use our blog to communicate this type of information, so we expect to keep this type of email to a minimum. If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. Mautic takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration, or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information (PII).

### Automatic Collection, Cookies & Web Beacons

Mautic or our service providers or our third party advertisers or links to third party websites and social media widgets may use automatic collection technologies including cookies and web beacons that collect information about you or your visits for purposes to improve your web activities or to deliver targeted content to you. Mautic does not provide personally-identifying information to these third parties and is not responsible or liable for nor do we endorse or control their activities. Use of third party links, advertisers, sites and/or widgets will be subject to the respective third party’s privacy policies and terms of service.

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Mautic uses cookies to help Mautic identify and track visitors, their usage of Mautic website, and their website access preferences. Mautic visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using Mautic’s websites, with the drawback that certain features of Mautic’s websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

Pages of this Website and any e-mails sent to you may contain web beacons. Web beacons (also referred to as clear gifs, pixel tags, and single-pixel gifs) are small electronic files that are embedded onto a web page or an email to document traffic and for website analytics without collecting any Personal Information, that, for example, allow us to count users who have visited webpages or opened our e-mails.

### Children’s Personal Information

This Website is not intended for children under 13 years of age. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13 without prior verifiable parental consent. If we learn that a child under the age of 13 has submitted personally identifiable information online without parental consent, we will take all reasonable measures to delete such information from our databases and to not use such information for any purpose (except where necessary to protect the safety of the child or others).

If you believe that a child under the age of 13 has provided us with personal information without verification of parental consent, please contact us at [help@mautic.org](mailto:help@mautic.org)

### Information Use, Access, Disclosure and Protections

We use your information, including any PII, to fulfill any other purposes for which you provide your information, for any other purpose as described to you at the time your information is collected or for which your consent is given or for any other purpose in our sole judgment to improve or enhance our user’s website experience or to improve our operations and obligations.

Nothing in this Privacy Policy is intended to interfere with our ability to transfer all or part of our business, equity interests, or assets (including this Website) to an affiliate or unaffiliated third party at any time, for any purpose, without any limitation, and without notice or any compensation to you.

The appropriate method(s) for accessing your information, if any, will depend on which of our websites and services you have visited or used. Depending on the website and service, you may have the ability to view or edit some of your information online, by logging into the website and visiting your account profile page. If you remove information from your user profile, it may stay in backups on our servers for a period before being completely removed. Once deleted, your account is gone and cannot be restored.

Public content you created, such as issues, forum posts, projects, documentation page revisions, etc. won’t be deleted. It is possible that all this posted content may be changed to attributed by ‘Anonymous’ user.

We use reasonable and customary security measures to protect your information collected through this Website. However, no method of transmission, electronic storage or security protocols is 100% safe, and we cannot guarantee absolute security. Therefore, your use of this Website or any products or services of Mautic is at your own risk and we do not promise or guarantee, and you should not expect, that your information would always and absolutely remain private and secure. We are not responsible for the circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures contained on or concerning this Website. You are also responsible for taking reasonable steps to protect your personal information against unauthorized disclosure or misuse.

### Privacy Policy Changes and Conditions of Use

In Mautic’s sole discretion this Privacy Policy may change from time to time. Mautic encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change. If you decide to visit Mautic’s websites, your visit and any possible dispute over privacy is subject to this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use, including limitations on damages, arbitration of disputes, and application of North Carolina, USA law.

### Contacting Us

If you have questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy, our information practices, or wish to make a request regarding your information, please contact us at any of the following:

Via postal mail:  
**Mautic Association**  
2810 Eric Lane, Burlington, NC 27215,  
United States of America

Via e-mail: [help@mautic.org](mailto:help@mautic.org)

* * *

Mautic’s Privacy Policy is modified from one originally attributed from WordPress, under an open license agreement. http://www.wordpress.org/about/privacy/ Such policy has been transformed for Mautic’s use and is not deemed an endorsement by WordPress.
